# **Yiren Jian**

### Research Scientist

ByteDance Inc.

🛮 yiren.jian.gr@dartmouth.edu 📗 🧥 yiren-jian.github.io 📘 🖫 yiren-jian

I am a research scientist at ByteDance Inc., specializing in multi-modal foundational models. My research encompasses a broad spectrum of topics within machine learning, with a particular focus on computer vision, natural language processing, and computational science. Specifically, my work involves continual pre-training and instruction fine-tuning of generative visual-language models, as well as applying AI and ML in various scientific domains.

# Professional Experience \_\_\_\_

Research Scientist, ByteDance Inc.

Bellevue, WA

 $Develop\ open-sourced\ visual\ language\ models\ for\ multimodal\ understanding.$ 

Feb. 2024 - Now

Manager: Hongxia Yang

Research Scientist Intern, ByteDance Inc.

Bellevue, WA

Develop efficient generative visual-language models based on LLM.

June. 2023 - Sept. 2023

Advisor: Yunzhe Tao

Research Scientist Intern, Snap Research at Snap Inc.

Palo Alto, CA

Develop neural speakers for affective image captioning.

June. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Advisor: Panos Achlioptas

**Research Scientist Intern, NEC Labs America** 

Princeton, NJ

Develop physical-augmented ML models for precision immunotherapy.

June. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Advisor: Martin Rengiang Min

## **Education**

Dartmouth College Hanover, NH, USA

Doctor of Philosophy - Computer Science Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2024

Advisor: Soroush Vosoughi

The George Washington University

Washington DC, USA

Master of Science - Biophysics Sept. 2015 - May. 2017

Advisor: Chen Zeng

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

Wuhan, China

Bachelor of Science - Physics Sept. 2011 - May. 2015

Thesis advisor: Yi Xiao

### **Publications**

#### InfiMM: Advancing Multimodal Understanding with an Open-Sourced Visual Language Model

[Findings of ACL 2024] Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics

Haogeng Liu, Quanzeng You, Yiqi Wang, Xiaotian Han, Bohan Zhai, Yongfei Liu, Wentao Chen, **Yiren Jian**, Yunzhe Tao, Jianbo Yuan, Ran He, Hongxia Yang

#### **Expedited Training of Visual Conditioned Language Generation via Redundancy Reduction**

[ACL 2024] The 62nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics

Yiren Jian, Tingkai Liu, Yunzhe Tao, Chunhui Zhang, Soroush Vosoughi, Hongxia Yang

#### **GEM: Generating Engaging Multimodal Content**

[IJCAI 2024] International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence

Chongyang Gao, Yiren Jian, Natalia Denisenko, Soroush Vosoughi, V.S. Subrahmanian

#### Efficient and Effective Learning of Foundational Large Multi-Modal Models

Dartmouth College PhD Dissertations, 2024

Yiren Jian

#### RNet: a network strategy to predict RNA binding preferences

Briefings in Bioinformatics, 2024

Haoquan Liu, **Yiren Jian**, Jinxuan Hou, Ceng Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

#### Bootstrapping Vision-Language Learning with Decoupled Language Pre-training

[NeurIPS 2023, \* spotlight] Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### Evaluation of DNA-protein complex structures using the deep learning method

Physical Chemistry and Chemical Physics, 2023

Chengwei Zeng#, **Yiren Jian**#, Chen Zhuo, Anbang Li, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

# Knowledge from Large-Scale Protein Contact Prediction Models Can Be Transferred to the Data-Scarce RNA Contact Prediction Task

preprint, 2023

**Yiren Jian**<sup>†</sup>, Chongyang Gao, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao, Soroush Vosoughi<sup>†</sup>

#### Evaluating Native-like Structures of RNA-protein Complexes Through the Deep Learning Method

Nature Communications, 2023

Chengwei  $Zeng^{\#}$ ,  $Yiren Jian^{\#}$ , Soroush Vosoughi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

#### **Non-Linguistic Supervision for Contrastive Learning of Sentence Embeddings**

[NeurIPS 2022] Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### T-Cell Receptor-Peptide Interaction Prediction with Physical Model Augmented Pseudo-Labeling

[KDD 2022, \*\* oral presentation] In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining

Yiren Jian, Erik Kruus, Martin Rengiang Min

#### **Embedding Hallucination for Few-shot Language Fine-tuning**

[NAACL 2022] In Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### **Contrastive Learning for Prompt-based Few-shot Language Learners**

[NAACL 2022] In Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies

**Yiren Jian**, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

#### **Label Hallucination for Few-Shot Classification**

[AAAI 2022] Proceedings of the 36th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence

**Yiren Jian**, Lorenzo Torresani

#### MetaPix: Domain Transfer for Semantic Segmentation by Meta Pixel Weighting

Image and Vision Computing, 2021

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao

#### **Task Meta-Transfer from Limited Parallel Labels**

Meta-Learning Workshop at Neural Information Processing Systems, 2020

Yiren Jian, Karim Ahmed, Lorenzo Torresani

#### **DIRECT: RNA Contact Predictions by Integrating Structural Patter**

BMC Bioinformatics, 2019

**Yiren Jian**, Xiaonan Wang, Jiadi Qiu, Huiwen Wang, Zhichao Liu, Yunjie Zhao, Chen Zeng

# Trace, Machine Learning of Signal Images for Trace-Sensitive Mass Spectrometry: A Case Study from Single-Cell Metabolomics

Analytical Chemistry, 2019

Zhichao Liu, Erika P. Portero, **Yiren Jian**, Yunjie Zhao, Rosemary M. Onjiko, Chen Zeng, Peter Nemes

#### **Design of Tat-activated Cdk9 Inhibitor**

Journal of Peptide Research and Therapeutics, 2019

Yunjie Zhao, Hao Chen, Chenghang Du, Yiren Jian, Haotian Li, Yi Xiao, Mohammed Saifuddin, Fatah Kashanchi, and Chen Zeng

#### Rbind: Computational Network Method to Predict the Binding Sites of RNA Molecules

Bioinformatics, 2018

Kaili Wang<sup>#</sup>, **Yiren Jian**<sup>#</sup>, Huiwen Wang, Chen Zeng and Yunjie Zhao

#### Computational Study of Non-catalytic T-loop Pocket on CDK Proteins for Drug Development

Chinese Physics B, 2017

Huiwen Wang, Kaili Wang, Zeyu Guan, **Yiren Jian**, Ya Jia, Fatah Kashanchi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

#### Network Analysis Reveals the Recognition Mechanism for Dimer Formation of Bulb-type Lectins

Scientific Report, 2017

Yunjie Zhao<sup>#</sup>, **Yiren Jian**<sup>#</sup>, Zhichao Liu, Hang Liu, Qin Liu, Chanyou Chen, Zhangyong Li, Lu Wang, H. Howie Huang, Chen Zeng

#### **Patents**

T-cell receptor repertoire selection prediction with physical model augmented pseudo-labeling (w/ NEC Labs America)

### **Academic Services**

- 2024 **Invited Reviewer,** European Conference on Computer Vision
- 2024 Invited Reviewer, Conference on Language Modeling
- 2024 Invited Reviewer, International Conference on Machine Learning
- 2024 Invited Reviewer, International Conference on Learning Representations
- 2024 Invited Reviewer, Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
- 2023 Invited Reviewer, Northern European Journal of Language Technology
- 2023 **Invited Reviewer**, IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision
- 2023 Invited Reviewer, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems
- 2023 External Reviewer, Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics

## **Teaching Experience**

2019, 2021 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Deep Learning (graduate-level course)	Dartmouth
2021-2023 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning (graduate-level course)	Dartmouth
2018 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning (graduate-level course)	Dartmouth
2015-2016 <b>Graduate Teaching Assistant</b> , University Physics (undergraduate course)	GWU

July 8, 2024 Yiren Jian · Résumé 3